<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>A Fine Dining (Posts about 황교익)</title><link>https://nrevival.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://nrevival.github.io/categories/hwanggyoig.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:nrevival@gmail.com"&gt;John Jonghyuck Park&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:02:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>혼밥러여 흩어지자!</title><link>https://nrevival.github.io/posts/honbapler/</link><dc:creator>John Jonghyuck Park</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;이것은 내가 전 회사 영어스터디에서 자유 작문 할 때, 나름 이슈가 되었던 황교익의 "혼밥러, 사회적 자폐"와 관련된 글을 끄적거려본 것. 공산당선언을 잘 이용해서 멋있게 쓰고 싶었는데 실패. 영어 능력자님들은 보다가 이상하면 comment를 남겨주세요. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;혼밥이라는 유령&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(한국어 버전은 아래)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spectre is haunting South Korea - the spectre of Honbap. 
(Honbap is a Korean neologism which means 'eating a meal alone')&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honbap culture is in debating. The discussion toward eating-a-meal-alone culture was started by a famous food columnist. He criticised the honbap culture on a radio show, "The homeless eat a meal alone, because they forgot a way of communication". The news caster asked again, "There are the people who want to have a meal alone in order to avoid emotional labour and stress caused by the social interactions." and he answered, "They should overcome it. We human, are an animal who cannot live without others. Though they want to escape the situation of emotional labour, being alone and hiding from others is an autism."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His opinion deserves to be agreed to a certain degree that human is a social animal. Nobody doesn't want to dine with one's closest friends and family. Even a coarse meal could be enjoyed with people whom we love. Despite this simple fact, our society doesn't allow us to have a meal together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honbap, a widespread culture of twenties and thirties, is a kind of necessary evil to be provided with energy and nutrients. They just strive to survive in the fierce struggle for existence. The living expenses are arising, but getting a decent job is 
extremely hard. All they could do is just saving money and time on their diets. Honbap is a good way to achieve the both goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for someone who get a job, Honbap is a good option to take a rest from others. Unlike Western culture, co-workers tend to meddle in other's private business when they have lunch. Eating a meal alone, in this manner, is a meager trial which might be unsuccessful due to seniors' interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food columnist's opinion is just an adultism. Every generations have different culture and circumstance. Measuring others with his/her own criterion is always committing mistake and a kind of violence. Before judging them as anti-social groups, he should try to understand the serious circumstance they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Honbapers have nothing to lose but their pokes. They have a tasty meal to win.
Honbapers of All Countries, Scatter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(절대 직역이 아니다 / Not literally translated )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;하나의 유령이 남조선을 배회한다. 바로 혼밥이라는 유령이다.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;혼밥과 관련해서 이 곳 저 곳이 시끄럽다. 아마 내 타임라인만 그런진 모르겠다. 모 예능프로로 유명해지다보니 예전 발언이 다시 이슈가 되었는데 "감정노동이 싫다고 해서 '나는 나 혼자 행동하겠다'고 하면 점점 숨어들지 않나. 그게 자폐다. 사회적 자폐"의 발언이 네티즌들 사이에서 논란이 되는 모양이다. 물론 내 타임라인은 논란이라기 보다는 비판이 주다.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;아무튼 황교익이 이야기한 내용에 아주 조그마한 동의를 하는 부분은 인간은 사회적 동물이라는 점, 혼밥 문화가 바람직하지 않을 수 있다는 내용이다. 누군들 두 세 시간씩 여유를 즐기며 잘 서빙되는 음식점에 앉아서 다른 사람과 이야기를 나누며 진미를 즐기는 것을 싫어할 사람이 있겠는가. 그게 아니라도 좋아하는 사람과 정답게 라면만 먹어도 행복한 것을 모르는 사람은 없을 터인데 그러한 면에서의 혼밥 비판은 수긍을 하겠다만.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;그러나 혼밥 비판은 현실을 전혀 반영하지 못하고 있다. 학생식당의 밥마저 비싸다고 느끼는 대학생들이 편의점 삼각김밥과 컵라면을 먹는 혼밥이 사회적 자폐인가? 오지랖 넓은 상위 직책자들과 먹으며 지난 주말을 공유해야 하는 스트레스를 피하려는 것이 정말로 진화를 퇴행하는 일이란 말인가. 아니, 사회가 이 모양이 되었는데 도리어 이러한 사회환경에 맞춘 훌륭한 적자(the fittest)의 행동이 아니라 무엇이란 말인가.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;글을 쓰다보니 다소 허수아비를 상정하고 싸운 것 같긴한데, 밥 좀 혼자 먹으면 어디가 덧나냐. 맞벌이 부부의 외동자녀는 저녁을 종종 혼자먹는데 - 내 이야기 - 그게 그렇게 자폐적인 행동인지.. 뭘 시비를 걸고 싶은건지도 모르겠고, 아무말 대잔치를 한건지. 물론 이것은 내 이야기기도 한데. 신경 쓰지말고 자기 삶을 열심히 살았으면 좋겠다.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;혼밥러들이 잃을 것은 꼰대들의 잔소리 뿐이요, 얻을 것은 맛점이다.
전 세계의 혼밥러들이여, 흩어지자!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>혼밥</category><category>황교익</category><guid>https://nrevival.github.io/posts/honbapler/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 03:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>